《女王》前情提要
Previously on Reign:
你见过他吗  你见过"黑暗"吗
Have you seen him? Have you seen the Darkness?
我生下来就是个异教徒
I was born a pagan.
所以你才对此事这么上心吗
Is that why you've taken this on?
这个信仰
Because you feel some blame
让你觉得要为森林中的罪行负责吗
for the blood spilled by this faith?
别  烦我
Leave... me alone.
他就是疯了
He is mad,
一个疯了的国王会引起混乱煽动叛乱的
and a mad king incites chaos and rebellion.
他听了我的话
He listened to me.
他已经开始恢复理智
His sanity started trickling back in,
有一瞬间  我甚至感觉到了曾经的父亲
and for a moment I could actually see my father again.
我得杀了我的儿子
I must kill my son
然后跟他妻子成婚
and wed his wife.
出什么事了
What's happening?
我很害怕  我不想去
I'm frightened. I don't want to go!
国王又发怒了吗
Is the king angry again?
怎么回事  城堡遭到攻击了吗
What's going on? Is the castle under attack?
国王召集所有人去庭院
The king has summoned everyone to the courtyard.
很紧急
Urgently.
怎么回事
What's this about?
我不知道  但恐怕是最糟糕的事
I don't know, but I fear the worst.
你们中有一个或者多个人
One or more of you here,
我的朋友  家人
my friends, my family...
臣民中
my subjects...
想杀害我
tried to kill me.
我已经采取了行动
I have taken steps.
你们见过我的新手下
You have seen my new men,
模仿罗马帝国的禁卫军
modeled after the Praetorian Guard of the Roman Emperors;
只忠于我
loyal only to me.
但我知道这还不够
But I knew more needed to be done.
罪人自会显现
The guilty revealed.
而今晚
And this night...
在梦里
in a dream...
上帝告诉了我方法
God told me how.
我向他发誓
My oath to him:
这把剑
this sword...
夺人性命之后
will not be sheathed
才会入鞘
till it has taken a life.
太阳升起时  这把剑会投射出阴影
As the sun rises, this sword will cast a shadow.
阴影指向谁
When that shadow touches the guilty...
谁就是罪人
I'll know.
现在不行
Not now.
给他们时间诉说罪孽和忏悔
Give them time to tell their sins and due penance.
让他们清洗干净灵魂
Let their souls be wiped clean;
上帝最喜欢那样
God likes that best.
大家都想忏悔
Everyone wants to confess.
这里的谁
Who here...
昨天忏悔了
made their confession yesterday?
我
I did.
特拉弗斯  陛下
Travers, my lord.
贝拉米大人的书记
Secretary to Lord Bellamy.
你昨晚和人私通了吗
Did you fornicate last night?
或者随便提起了上帝的名字
Or take the Lord's name in vain?
当然没有  陛下
Of course not, my lord.
我们都该和你一样心甘情愿
We should all be as ready as you.
解散
Be off.
穿上最华丽的服饰
Done your finest clothing.
对加来胜利的庆祝
The celebrations of our victory at Calais
将达到巅峰
will reach their peak.
弄干净了
Clean that.
我错了
I was wrong.
他的确疯了
He is lost.
女王  第一季第二十二集
我长这么大
All the time I was growing up,
一直认为他是法国最伟大的男人
I saw him as the greatest man in France.
很抱歉  弗朗西斯
I'm sorry, Francis.
现在行刺太晚了  我们没法近他的身
It's too late for assassination; we'd never get near him.
必须由更大的力量来推翻他的王位
He must be removed from the throne by a superior force.
政变吗
A coup?
如果我们失败了  就死定了
It's deadly for us if we lose
如果成功了  也很危险
and dangerous if we win.
政变将权力交到了军队手里
A coup puts power in the hands of the military.
我们别无选择
We have no choice.
怎么做呢
But how?
我能给将军什么  让他们支持我  而不是我父亲
What can I offer the generals to back me, rather than Father?
我没法比他给他们更多奖赏了
I can give them no more reward than he.
加来战役之前  一些将军被撤职了
Some generals were dismissed before Calais.
他们肯定觉得被国王背叛了
Surely, they feel betrayed by their king.
他们都是有领地的贵族
And each one of them is a noble with a territory
而且还有自己的手下
and men of their own to command.
可能成功
It could work.
但如果我们获胜
But if we win,
夺取了政权
if we seize power...
你的父亲会怎么样
what happens to your father?
他会被囚禁起来
He will be imprisoned,
看最好的医生
see the finest doctors,
不久后  他要么会恢复正常
and in time either he will regain his senses
要么会自然死亡  但是...
or he will die a natural death, but...
他不能再做国王了
he can never be king again.
他的年代会终结...
His time will be over...
你我将共同执政
and you will rule beside me.
帕斯卡尔
Pascal.
怎么了  出什么事了
What is it, what's wrong?
我做噩梦了
I've had a nightmare.
我看见他
I saw him...
站在窗外  盯着我们
outside the window, staring at us.
瞧见了吗
You see?
巴斯派来的守卫在这里
The guards that Bash sent are here.
你很安全  那只是梦而已
You're safe. It was just a dream.
巴斯很快会从维斯嘉德回来
Bash will return from Visegard soon.
等他找到"黑暗"
And when he finds the Darkness,
你就再也不用害怕了
we'll make sure he never threatens you
别人也一样
or anyone else ever again.
我发现你的伤口痊愈了
Your wounds have healed, I see.
也没理由再窝在床上偷懒了
Well, I found no more excuses to stay in bed.
我还...
I also, um...
我发现了这个
I found this.
这是包括农田  果园  庄园在内的
It's a deed to lands that include farms,
土地地契
orchards, a manor house.
这叫我该怎么感谢你
How could I ever thank you?
我做梦到没想到...
This is more than I could have ever dreamed...
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
唯一让我后悔的是无法给你头衔
I only regret that I couldn't give you a title,
但只有国王有权这么做  而我父亲...
but that is the king's job and my father is...
现在这种黑暗时刻
These are dark hours;
不是让我父亲赐头衔的好时机
it is not a good time to ask for such a thing.
我们一定得喝一杯
We must share a drink.
我还有要事
I have something important to attend to.
下次吧
Another time?
对了  祝你成功娶到你说的那个姑娘
Oh, good luck with that girl that you told me about.
如果她不马上嫁给你  她就是个傻瓜
If she doesn't wed you now, she's a fool.
那杯酒是我给你拿来的
I brought you that drink.
你不觉得至少该对我笑一笑吗
Don't you think you owe me a smile?
又不是我让你拿的
I didn't ask for the drink.
你尽管拿回去啊
Feel free to take it back.
你大错特错了
You're making an enormous mistake,
你个婊子
you rich tart.
我可是国王的贴身侍卫
I am in the king's personal guard.
你最好对我友好一点
So you'd better start being nice to me,
-这样对你自己好...  -亲爱的
- if you know what's best... - Darling!
抱歉我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
没关系
It's all right.
这位先生在陪我解闷呢
This gentleman was just keeping me amused.
好吧
Well...
美女
only the best
要配加来之战的英雄
for the heroes of Calais...
对吧
right?
抱歉冒昧打扰了
Sorry for intruding.
有人被强迫做一些不愿做的事时
I can tell when somebody's being pushed into something
我能看出来  这种事我见过太多
that they don't want to do; I've seen too much of it.
你是说在军队时吗
In the army, you mean?
在我的一生中
All my life.
跟我喝一杯  然后跟我说说吧
Have a drink with me and tell me about it.
我  我很愿意  但是
I... I'd love to, but, uh...
说实话  我  我在找人
I-- truth is, I'm-I'm looking for someone.
这是今天我听过的最悲伤的话了
Those are the saddest words I've heard all day.
陛下  我按照您的吩咐做好了
Your Majesty, I've done as you wished.
往王子盘子里下药的事
The matter of the additional spice to be added
您确定真的要这么做吗
to the Dauphin's plate, have you changed your mind?
确定
No.
今晚的晚宴上就动手
I want it done at tonight's feast.
不用担心犯下罪恶
Don't be concerned about the sin.
我已经为我们两人向上帝赎罪了
I reconciled with God for us both.
记住要让他的盘子里堆满肉
See his plate is piled high with meats.
好让别人以为弗朗西斯
To those watching, it will look as though
是被噎死的
Francis choked to death.
对了  告诉下人准备好花环
Oh! And tell them to leave up the garlands.
我打算在这里举办婚礼
I'm planning a wedding here...
就在不久的将来
in the near future.
如果我能说服将军们支持我
If I can sway the generals to my side,
我就会跟他们还有他们派的人一起返回
I shall return with them and their men beside me.
这样就够了吗
Will that be enough?
如果吉斯公爵与我们为敌...
If the Duke of Guise sets his forces against us...
他为人谨慎
He is a cautious man.
可能会等等看看是谁赢得这场...
Perhaps he'll wait to see who wins this...
瞧啊
Well!
这么美好的日子里有两对幸福的夫妻
Two happy couples on a happy day, hmm?
玛丽
Mary,
你不来看看马上长矛比武
aren't you coming to see the joust
还有海军的壮观表演吗
and the naval spectacle?
什么壮观表演
"Spectacle"?
两艘战船
Two ships
模拟战役
in mock combat.
绝对会是奇观
It will be a wonder.
而你  就是此次奇观的贵客
And you... are the guest of honor.
我
Me?
亨利坚持让你去看  亲爱的
Oh, Henry insists, my dear.
当然  这是我的荣幸
Oh, of course, I'm honored.
我很后悔之前跟你不怎么亲近
I regret we haven't been as close as we should.
可能因为你跟我儿子在一起
I may have been a bit judgmental
以及你跟他至今
in your behavior with my sons
没有子嗣的事  我对你
and about your lack of an heir...
有点偏见...
with Francis.
可事实证明
As it turns out,
上帝这样计划可能...
God's plan there may be...
是最好的选择
for the best, after all.
-我该走了  -你不能走
- I should go. - But, you can't.
你不仅是加来一战的英雄
You're not just a hero of Calais,
你还是战役的领导者
you led the invasion.
我要去探望在战役中受伤
I am looking in at some of the injured soldiers
今天无法到场的将士
who couldn't be here today.
那你今晚会回来参加晚宴的对吧
But you will be back for the feast... tonight?
当然
Of course.
走吧
Shall we?
进来
Come in!
你把盘子放到那边的桌子上就行
Could you put the tray on the table over there?
是行
I could,
但我没拿盘子
but I don't have a tray.
要我去拿一个来吗
Should I go find one?
利思
Leith.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
我听说你还活着  但是
I heard you were alive, but...
这是什么
What's this?
我的土地
My land.
你看看地图上
Look at the map.
你看看所列物品
Look at the list of holdings.
农田  付租金的租客
Farms, tenants paying rent!
河流  果园  庄园
River access, orchards, a manor house.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我是加来战役的英雄  葛瑞尔
I'm a hero of Calais, Greer.
我救了王子的命
I saved the Dauphin's life.
弗朗西斯称我为他的朋友
Francis calls me his friend.
太好了
This is wonderful.
但这...
But it...
并不能改变什么
it can't change anything.
我已经和卡斯尔雷大人订婚了
I'm engaged to Lord Castleroy.
什么...我现在有钱了
Wha-- I'm-I'm a rich man.
你的确能为我提供舒适的生活
You are a... a comfortable man.
但你的财产
But this w...
连我父亲欠的债的十分之一都不够
would not clear a tenth of my father's debts.
也负担不起我妹妹们的嫁妆
It wouldn't provide my sisters with dowries.
我父亲会把她们卖给出价最高的人
My father would sell them to the highest bidder.
她们可以和我们一起生活
Well, they... well, they could live with us!
你不明白我们这种人的生活
You don't understand how people like us live!
我的妹妹们属于我的父亲
My sisters belong to my father;
是他的私人财产
they're his property!
他绝不会同意让她们搬去
He'd never agree to let them move to--
一个在他看来
what he'd see as some...
像死水一样的
...some backwater,
没法让她们找到合适求婚者的地方
where they would never find appropriate suitors.
我明白了
I get the idea.
请你理解
Please understand.
我还要去港口
I'm... due in the harbor.
他们想让我
They want me to...
和其他一些老兵一起上船  类似某种
join some other veterans on the ship; some kind of...
宏大的海军展示
naval spectacle.
看来还是有人会把今天视为庆典
Apparently, there are people who consider today a celebration.
我不希望我们就这样分别
I don't want to part like this!
葛瑞尔  某些时候  你需要停止
Greer, at some point, you have to stop piling
把整个家族的问题都堆在自己身上
all of your family's problems on your back.
你需要去冒险
You have to take a risk.
你需要相信爱  相信命运
You have to trust love and fate
相信我
and me.
对不起  夫人
Uh, I beg your pardon, ma'am.
我在驾驶马车
My carriage is in the road.
送一位贵妇人返回城堡时
I'm taking a noblewoman back to the castle,
可她突然快要分娩
and she has gone into labor.
夫人
Uh, my lady,
你该等我去接你的
you should've waited for me to get you.
你们干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
我没法帮你们
I can't help you!
我不是接生婆
I'm not a midwife.
那就去找一个来
Then send for one.
我会补偿给你造成的麻烦
I can reimburse you for your trouble.
如果这位夫人或她的孩子死在这里
What reimbursement will help me
我要补偿又有什么用呢
if this lady dies on my hands?
整个法国都将怪罪于我
Or her babe, and all of France will blame me.
法国国王  亨利陛下
His Majesty King Henry of France.
苏格兰女王  玛丽陛下
Her Majesty Mary, Queen of Scots.
法国王后  凯瑟琳陛下
Her Majesty Catherine, Queen of France.
睁大你们的眼睛  看看法国的力量吧
Turn your eyes on a display of French might.
这场展示是为了向加来之战的英雄们致敬
A spectacle to honor the heroes of Calais.
每艘船上
Each ship is full of soldiers
都满载着凯旋的士兵
just returned from our victory.
国王万岁
Long live the king!
等着看烟火吧
Wait till you see the fireworks.
愿上帝保佑你  国王陛下
God bless you, Your Majesty!
有什么我能为你做的吗  亲爱的
Is there anything I can get you, my dear?
要不要来点温暖
Some warm...
香甜的葡萄酒
mulled wine?
不用了  谢谢  我很好
No, thank you. I'm fine.
利思刚刚来找我了
Leith came to see me.
我向他表明我们之间已经结束了
I made it clear to him that we're over,
我会嫁给你  你是我的未来
that I'm marrying you, that you're my future.
能不失去我心爱的女人真让我松了一口气
You must allow me to be relieved in not losing the woman I love.
他们竟然让加农炮开火
They're firing cannons.
太奇怪了
How strange.
我还以为他们会放烟火
I thought they were using fireworks.
一定是因为
It must be safe enough,
只要他们不互相瞄准  就足够安全
as long as they don't point at each other.
加农炮可是很难控制的
Well, cannons can be hard to control.
这是胜利的声音
The sound of victory.
是法国的声音
The sound of France.
这难道不让你觉得兴奋吗
Doesn't that excite you?
天呐  利思就在其中一艘船上
My God, Leith is on one of those ships.
就算是没被炸成碎片的人也活不下来了
Those who aren't blown to bits won't survive.
-水太冷了  -我告诉过他们要小心了
- The water's freezing. - I told them to fire with care!
控制开火的人难道是宠物猴吗
Who's manning the guns, a pet monkey?
等等  你真的让他们开火了
Wait, you actually told them to fire the cannons?
只有烟火
What kind of spectacle
算得上什么宏大展示呢
would mere fireworks have been, hmm?
无所谓了
Well, never mind.
我不许你失望  玛丽
I refuse to have you disappointed, Mary.
这些...
This...
都是为你而准备的
is all for you, you know.
-明天还有一次机会  -明天
- There'll be another chance tomorrow. - Tomorrow?
明天我们会再来一次  这回一定要成功
When we'll do it again! Properly this time!
上百人就这么死去了
A hundred men dead like that.
生命被如此轻易地夺去
Life so carelessly taken.
感觉好像我是那个失去了理智的人一样
I feel like I'm the one losing my mind.
玛丽  有件事你需要知道
Mary, there's something you should know.
亨利再一次申请废后
Henry asked for an annulment once more.
这只能说明他打算结束我们的婚姻
It can only mean he wishes to end our marriage
另娶他人
and turn to someone else.
也就是你
You.
不
No.
我看到了他对你的所作所为
I saw what he did to you.
这简直是莫名其妙
That came out of nowhere.
他从未对我表现出丁点兴趣
He's never shown the slightest bit of interest.
一旦他娶了你  他就能够染指英格兰
When he had his hands on you, he had his hands on England.
所以他决定娶我
So he's decided to wed me,
让三个国家都归他所有
then keep all three crowns for himself.
所以他才突然慷慨地接受了
Thus his suddenly generous acceptance
你没有怀孕这件事
of the fact that you are not pregnant...
至今没有怀孕
yet.
他想亲自让你怀上子嗣
He wants to give you an heir himself.
还有那个如同大屠杀一样的展示
And the spectacle, the carnage...
-拙劣的展示出他的威武  -难道他真认为
- Botched display of his prowess. - Does he honestly think
我和弗朗西斯会同意废除我们的婚姻吗
that Francis and I would agree to have our marriage annulled?
这简直太荒谬了
It's ridiculous!
不
No.
他不会这样做的
Even he wouldn't.
他要杀害自己的亲生儿子
He's going to kill his own son!
如果你所料不错的话
If you're right,
我们只有一个机会
our only chance
那就是拿下他和他的卫兵
is to overtake him and his guards.
假设弗朗西斯能够说服那些将军
Assuming that Francis is able to persuade the generals
和我们一起进行政变
to join us in a coup.
如果弗朗西斯回来时
If Francis comes back
走在军队前面  我们就知道他成功了
at the head of an army, we'll know he succeeded.
如果他孤身回来
If he comes back alone,
我们就根本无法反抗亨利
we have no protection from Henry,
弗朗西斯也是如此
and neither does Francis.
说你呢
You there,
这是怎么回事
what's this?
What is this?
发生了什么
What happened here?
我请求你们  实话实说
I beg of you, speak freely.
殿下  这就是史上最壮观的海上奇观展示
The greatest naval spectacle of all time, my lord.
直到船爆炸之前
That is, until the ship exploded.
国王用火药取代了烟花
The king replaced the fireworks with gunpowder.
他们在加来逃过一劫  到来来确是这样
Can you believe they survived Calais for this?
这些士兵都是去过加来的吗
These soldiers are from Calais?
明天再次展示时  人数就会翻倍了
There'll be twice as many tomorrow when they do it again.
这不可能
That's impossible.
-谁也不准再进行一次  -请您原谅
- No one would do this again. - Begging your pardon,
但你肯定没想到
but you would think no one
会有人第一次做出这种事情对吗
would do it the first time, wouldn't you?
但你得想想
Still, you've got to wonder
谁更可怜
who's worse off,
是这些可怜人
these poor fellows
还是那些准备起航去英格兰的
or the ones shipping off for England.
至少他们还能死个痛快
At least for them it was quick.
谁也不准起航
No one is shipping out.
这是国王的旨意
King's orders.
你这话还是留给那3000个
Tell that to the 3,000 men
明晚就起航的人听吧
leaving tomorrow night.
你想让我加入你们的政变
You want me to join a coup?
也许今天你还能得到亨利的宠幸
You may have Henry's favor today,
但不会长久
but it can't last.
国王的行为一日比一日更癫狂
The king's behavior is getting more erratic every day.
他疯了的消息会散播出去
News of his madness will spread,
觊觎王位的人会陆续出现
contenders for the throne will appear,
内战肯定会不可避免
and civil war will follow, one way or another.
我理解你的逻辑
And I can't disagree with your logic,
但如果我们要成功进行政变的话
but we lack one essential element
我们还缺少一个要素
for a successful coup.
一位近在眼前而且有所准备的领袖
A leader ready and at hand
他得在国王去世之时填补王位的空缺
to fill the power vacuum once the king is gone.
领袖当然是弗朗西斯了
Well, Francis will be the leader, obviously.
他就是下一任国王
He'll be the next king.
弗朗西斯会因他父亲的错背上污名
Francis carries the stain of his father's mistakes.
他身上具备政变所反对的一切
He represents everything the coup would be against.
我们需要一位能凝聚整个国家的贵族
We need someone the nobles and the nation can rally around.
而你  玛丽  就是这个王国的希望
You, Mary, bring the promise of empire.
好好把握机会  用不了多久
Use the promise that someday soon,
英格兰所有的权利和财富就尽在你手中了
England and all its power and riches will be yours.
好好把握这个机会
Use this to make yourself
让自己成为法国最有权利的人
the most powerful person in France.
权利比我丈夫还大吗
More powerful than my husband?
如果你想要拥有一个国家
If you want to lay claim to a nation,
那就拿下法国吧
take France.
黑暗怎么会
Why would the Darkness
把一个小男孩带到这里来呢
bring a young boy to this place?
房屋尽毁
Every house deserted.
这些人都怎么了
What happened to these people?
一年前  这个地区被洪水淹没
The area was beset by flood a year ago.
这个镇子处在高地
The town sits on higher ground.
为什么却没人到这里来住呢
Why did no one settle here?
不是完全被废弃
Not entirely deserted.
这家人原来是住在这里的
The family that once lived here.
从这恶臭来看  我敢说还有另一个受害者
From the stench, I'd say there was another victim.
这是帕斯卡尔的围巾
Pascal's scarf.
这个祭品不久之前刚死的
This sacrifice is fresh,
几天前吧
a few days old.
帕斯卡尔身上的血肯定是他的
This is where the blood on Pascal came from.
从灰尘看  这些画早就有了
From the dirt, these picture have been here a long time.
风暴
A storm...
大火
fire...
-洪水  -灾难
- flood. - Disasters.
-为什么画在这里  -这应该是在叙述
- But why draw them here? - I think they may be depictions
真实发生在这片土地上的事吧
of actual events that occurred in this region.
大风暴
The Great Storm?
差不多是20年前的事了
Nearly two decades ago.
几年后  一场大火肆虐
Years later, the fire that raged
摧毁了昂热和附近的森林
destroyed Angers and the nearby forests.
洪水淹没了周边所有地区
The flood that wiped out the surrounding areas.
还有被遮住的太阳
And the blackening of the sun.
日食是最近发生的事情
The eclipse so recently witnessed.
这些是预言吗
Are these predictions?
是准确的预言
Accurate predictions.
这是什么意思
What does this one mean?
星辰从空中坠落
Stars falling from the sky.
我不知道
I don't know,
但只剩这一个未解了
but it's the only one left.
这是异教徒的韵文
It's a pagan rhyme.
我听到帕斯卡尔自己念唱过
I heard Pascal chanting it to himself.
我在星空下安躺
"I lie behind the star-bright sky.
不怕此生与过往
"I do not fear this life's good-bye.
闭眼感受我的爱抚
"Close your eyes for my caress...
因为我就是黑暗
for I am the Darkness."
我在星空下安躺
"I lie behind the star-bright sky.
不怕此生与过往
I do not fear this life's good-bye."
帕斯卡尔  为什么又在吟诵这几句韵文
Pascal, why are you saying that rhyme again?
你害怕了吗
Are you scared?
太安静了
It's too quiet.
卫兵都去哪了
Where are the guards?
快走  快走
Come on! Come on!
快啊
Come on!
快点
退后
Get back!
卫兵
Guards!
卫兵  救命啊
Guards, help!
你的卫兵已经死了
Your guards are dead,
你很快就会见到他们
and soon you will be, too,
但是这个男孩会活下去
but the boy will survive.
把他给我
Give him to me.
求你了  放过我们吧
Please leave us!
不行
I cannot.
我是黑暗
I am the Darkness,
是吞噬者
the Devourer,
是众神的侍奉者
the feeder of the gods,
但我不能永远侍奉他们
but I cannot feed them forever.
帕斯卡尔
Pascal,
把她的血献给众神
offer her blood to the gods.
在他们的欲望膨胀之前安抚一下
Appease their hunger before it grows.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
这是船上所有军官的名单
I have a list of the officers on the boat.
你家男人叫什么名字
What's your bloke's name?
他叫利思・贝亚德  但我觉得他不是军官
Leith Bayard, but I don't think he was an officer.
步兵应该在另一个地方
The foot soldiers are laid out elsewhere.
-我可以带你去  -葛瑞尔
- I can show you. - Greer!
你活下来了  你还活着
You survived. You survived.
所以大家才喜欢看马上长矛比武
This is why the people love a joust.
在久战之后  看皇室成员
Seeing nobles knocked on their asses
倒在地上
after a long war.
蒙特格利伯爵又打败了一个对手
Ah, Lord Montgomery takes down another opponent.
大家都去哪里了
Where is everybody?
他们为什么都这么低落
And why are they all so dour?
这是骑马比武  不是葬礼
They're at a joust, not a funeral.
因为你的模拟战  很多人失去了亲人  亨利
Many of them lost loved ones in your mock battle, Henry.
向玛丽女王致敬
Hail Queen Mary.
谢天谢地
Good God, finally.
是英格兰皇冠  玛丽
It's the English crest. Mary!
天哪  她穿着英格兰大衣
My God, she's wearing the English coat of arms.
苏格兰女王
The Queen of Scotland!
她一定是打算在英格兰称王了
She's all but declaring herself England's queen.
玛丽  玛丽
Mary! Mary!
我们就知道  只需一件表明身份的衣服
Who knew all it took was a statement dress
法国就会在她的股掌之中
to get France in the palm of her hands.
她代表着未来
She is the future.
他们看到了
They see that.
我看不到她
I can't see her!
你准备好了  是吧
You're ready, aren't you?
简直就像我们做着同样的梦
It's like we dream the same dreams.
玛丽  玛丽  玛丽女王万岁
Mary, Mary! Long live Queen Mary!
玛丽女王
Queen Mary!
她真的要继承英格兰吗
Is she really taking England?
他们已经失控了
They've lost control of themselves.
他们忘记了国王是谁吗
Have they forgotten who the king is?
我来给他们调节一下气氛
I'll give them something to cheer for.
暂停比赛
Halt the competition!
我要跟蒙特格利伯爵比一场
I am going to joust Lord Montgomery.
裁判
Gamekeeper...
但是  国王陛下  他的盔甲破损了
But, Your Majesty, his armor's damaged,
而且需要换一匹马
he'll need a fresh horse.
那你快点去办啊
Then you have much to attend to.
英格兰的人陆续离开了
Members of the English contingent are leaving.
他们要去警告伊丽莎白
Off to warn Elizabeth.
但愿你知道你在做什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
派你的骑兵跟踪他们
Send your riders after theirs.
如果他们中途停下  应该能发现法国境内的
If they stop, they may reveal some English sympathizers
英国支持者
amongst the French.
你这是置你表亲伊丽莎白于死地
You're squeezing your cousin Elizabeth's throat,
为了什么
and to what end?
给人们希望
To give the people hope.
让他们想象一个更好的未来
So they can imagine a brighter future.
你说得好听
Such glory you promise.
你现在已经如此贪婪
And so cunning you've become.
你从修道院回来之后  变了太多
How you've changed since you came back to us from convent.
我想念曾经的你
I miss the girl you were.
很多人都会的
Many will.
因为她更容易被杀
She was easier to kill.
我爱你  我爱你
I love you. I love you.
-我去把门关上  -关着呢
- I have to secure the door. - It's locked.
那我帮你脱衣服吧
Let me help you undress.
你  你就抱抱我
Please, just... just hold me,
多抱一会  好吗
a little more, please.
我们没必要停下来
We have no reason to stop.
我想娶你
I want to marry you.
葛瑞尔  不要这样
Greer, don't do this.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
我没死
I'm not.
我活生生地站在你面前
I'm standing right here before you,
你不应该再赶我走
and you should not let me go.
不管是为了钱  为了你的家人  或是什么
Not for money, or your family, or anything.
什么都没变
Nothing's changed,
我只是无比深切地感受到了
except I felt the pain of your loss more deeply
你曾经的痛苦
than I ever thought I could.
没错
And you will.
我发誓  葛瑞尔
I swear to you, Greer,
如果你不抓住这次机会  你还会痛不欲生
if you don't take this chance with me, you will.
嫁给我
Marry me.
嫁给我吧
Marry me!
不  利思  不行
No, Leith, I can't.
我不能
I can't!
等你感到孤独痛苦的时候
When you are alone and miserable,
记得  从这一刻起
remember this is the moment
是你亲手葬送了你的幸福
that you threw your happiness away.
我也不会忘记
And I'll remember you as the woman
你说我配不上你
who told me I wasn't enough.
我会拥有一切
I will become everything
能满足你的一切
you are so convinced that you need.
我会青云直上  飞黄腾达
I will rise and rise and rise,
直到拥有无上的财富与权力
until I am rich and powerful.
但你再也得不到我了
But I will never be yours again.
您的长矛  国王陛下
Your lance, Your Highness.
亨利国王陛下
His Majesty King Henry
对阵蒙特格利伯爵
and Lord Montgomery.
蒙特格利这是自讨苦吃
I suppose that's good comeuppance for Montgomery.
等着被狠狠击败吧
He will have to take the blows...
在统治者面前卖弄可没好下场
it's bad business to outshine your boss.
亨利国王
King Henry!
老天呐  快去看看他
For God's sake, go to him!
国王还好吗
Is the king all right?
陛下  陛下
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
国王陛下
Your Majesty!
国王身受重伤
The king has been gravely injured!
医生都去哪儿了
Where is the physician?!
国王陛下
Your Majesty...
没事了
It's all right.
我来了  你们受伤了吗
I'm here. Are you hurt?
没有  不过...巴斯  当心
No, but... Bash, look out!
带肯娜和帕斯卡尔离开
Get Kenna and Pascal out of here.
帕斯卡尔必须接任我
Pascal must succeed me,
不然黑死病会席卷而来
or the Black Death will awaken.
黑死病
The Black Death.
一场鼠疫
The plague.
维斯嘉德的种种迹象都预示着它的到来
That's what the signs at Visegard were counting down to.
巴斯  我看到过幻象
Bash, I've had visions.
城堡被死亡所笼罩  走廊上躺满了尸体
The castle beset by death. Bodies laid out in the hall.
如果我不完成任务  惨象就会发生
It will happen, if my work is not done.
看好肯娜和帕斯卡尔  快点
Stay with Kenna and Pascal, please.
能预见未来的天资少之又少
How rare is the gift of sight.
我不相信你可以
I don't believe you have it.
你是个杀手
I think you're a killer,
只会利用别人的恐惧
feeding on others' fears.
你也是异教徒
You're pagan-born.
嘴上抵赖也好  但在你内心
Deny it, but in your heart
你深知神明掌控着一切
you know the gods have power.
他们需要尊重
They demand respect.
需要血祭
Blood.
如果得不到...
And if they don't get it...
是你贪图鲜血  而非神明
You took the blood, not the gods.
我是来救你的
I'm here to save you.
我带领我的人进入血泊森林
I took my people into the Blood Wood
教给他们如何供奉神明
and showed them how to feed the gods,
从那时起鼠疫再没爆发过
and since that day the plague has not returned.
是神明控制住了瘟疫
But the gods hold it leashed,
在暗处看着我们
in the shadows,
如果我死后没有继任者
and if I die without a successor,
瘟疫便会卷土重来
it will run wild over the land.
把帕斯卡尔交给我
Bring Pascal to me,
我会拯救这个世界
and I will save your world.
他父亲知道这是他的使命
His father knew it was his fate.
-他知道这是无上的光荣  -不行
- He understood the honor. - No.
不能伤害无辜的孩子
No more children,
再没有所谓的献祭
no more sacrifices,
我要结束你残忍的杀戮
and the slaughter of innocents ends here.
不会结束的
It can't end!
他还活着吗
Does he live yet?
弥留之际
He lingers.
他们说  可能撑不过去了
He won't survive; they say he can't.
一段长矛刺进了他的大脑
There's pieces of the lance stuck in his brain.
这是我们造成的吗
Is this what we wanted?
不是
It isn't.
亨利被刺落马下不是我们能控制的
Henry's fall was out of our hands completely.
这难道不是神的旨意吗
Is that not God's will?
不会再有人献出生命了
Now no more blood needs to be spilled.
除了我父亲
None but my father's.
我们去跟他道别吧
We should say good-bye.
不管我们感情如何
In spite of our feelings,
我所做的一切都是为了
I've always tried to do what's been best
我们的孩子和你
for our children and for you.
也是为了法国
And for France.
没什么好遗憾的
Shh, there are no more regrets.
一直以来  我都是爱你的
In my way, I have always loved you.
你是我此生的至爱
You are the love of my life.
你又变得如此仁慈了
Oh, to see your kindness returned...
你也是
Yours must, as well.
你内心一直如此
It's in you still.
以后对黛安也要仁慈些
You must show it to Diane.
我走后  她就无依无靠了
She is unprotected once I'm gone.
我的...我们的生活中  她占据了大部分
After being so much a part of my life, of ours...
你们谁都不该感到孤独
neither of you should be alone.
在整个大家族中  很多时候...
She is extended family, your equal in s...
她都与你平起平坐
so many ways.
凯瑟琳
Catherine...
对她友好些
...be friends.
请照顾好她
Please reach out to her.
好吧
Yes.
我会照顾她的
I will reach out to her.
休息吧  亨利
Rest now, Henry.
放心去吧
Rest long.
把弗朗西斯叫来
Francis, now.
让他单独过来
Just Francis.
弗朗西斯  你有什么要对我说的吗
Francis, what have you come to say to me?
每一个错误  都必须纠正吗
Must we right every wrong?
我听不懂您的意思  父亲
I'm not sure what you mean, Father.
看看你
Oh, it's you.
我有没有说过  你的名字跟我兄长一样
Did I tell you that you were named after my elder brother?
他本来要当国王的
He was to be king.
他害怕当国王
He feared the job,
害怕要因此夺取人的生命
the giving and taking of lives to a cause.
他这方面也很像你
He was like you in that way, too.
我觉得他很软弱
I thought him weak.
我知道我能成为更好的国王
I knew I would be a better king.
自始至终都是一场较量
It was a competition all along.
权利的游戏  对至亲之人最严苛
Such games we play against those we love.
我大获全胜
I won it all.
在一个网球场上
On a tennis court of all places.
我往他的水里下了毒
When he collapsed
他很快就死了
after I poisoned his water.
你杀了你哥哥
You killed your brother.
没有人知道
No one ever knew.
我终于知道你为何要我小心自己的兄弟
Now I know why you warned me against my brother.
让我和塞巴斯蒂安反目
Turned me against Sebastian.
背叛你爱的人
Betraying someone you love
会污染你的灵魂
blackens your soul.
这种负担
It's a weight you carry
要背一辈子
all of your days.
我现在可以放开了吗
Can I let it go now?
上帝原谅我
God forgive me.
国王已死
The king is dead.
国王万岁
Long live the king!
国王已死  国王万岁
The king is dead. Long live the king!
你好啊
Well, hello there.
我是利思  还记得我吗
Leith. Do you recall?
我叫伊薇特  和"当然记得"押韵
Yvette. Rhymes with "How could I forget?"
根据祝酒和流言所说
A new government is forming
新政权正在崛起
between toasts and whispers.
这值得干一杯
So let's have that drink now.
发生了什么吗
What changed?
上次我们见面时  你走得很匆忙
You were in such a hurry when last we met.
我那时还不渴
I wasn't thirsty then.
现在渴了
I am now.
下次吧
Another time.
等会儿我要见另一个人
As this hour, I am destined to meet another.
-真让我心碎啊  -怎么会呢
- Aren't you a heartbreaker? - Not at all.
你也不要让我心碎哦
Don't you be one, either.
你迟到了
You're late.
只迟了一会儿
Only barely.
我等了你这么久  无聊透顶
I couldn't leave right away as I'd spent hours
我不能马上离开
waiting for you, bored senseless,
突然  我...
and then suddenly, I...
父亲
Oh, Father.
今晚发生了最奇妙的逆转
My evening took the loveliest turn.
村里面传信来了
Word's back from the village.
接生婆生病了  没办法过来
The midwife's taken ill herself and is no condition to travel.
宝宝马上就要出生了
The baby should have come by now.
没错  应该是这样
Yes. It should have.
我担心他不能活下来  你也一样
I fear for its life, and yours as well.
我不想吓着你
I don't mean to scare you.
但你有没有想留下来的话
Are there words you want written down
以防万一
in case?
有
Yes.
但有没有什么办法
But if there's any way
可以救下这个孩子...
you can save the baby...
那些方法都会杀了你
None that wouldn't kill you.
我也没有其他办法
Or that I'm equipped for.
我亲爱的朋友  玛丽
"My dear friend, Mary.
我孤身一人  我的孩子拼命地
"I am alone and my child struggles
想来到这个世界
"to join this world.
你不用再遵守你的承诺了
"I release you from your promise,
也不用再因为我们的秘密保护我
"from the protection our secret gave me.
因为朱利安已经死了
"For Julien has died.
我可能马上就会见到他了
"And I'm afraid I may soon join him.
请前来救助我
"Please, bring help.
但如果我死去  但孩子活了下来
"But if I die and the child survives,
请照顾我的孩子  视如己出
"care for my baby as if it were your own.
和弗朗西斯一起照顾他
With Francis."
你的朋友是玛丽  苏格兰女王吗
Your friend is Mary, Queen of Scots?
没错
Yes.
请把这信带到城堡去
Please, have it taken to the castle.
快点
And hurry!
巴斯
Bash.
关于你父亲的事  我很遗憾
I'm so sorry about your father.
我不知道我的容身之处在哪里
I don't know what my place is here anymore.
你应该和我在一起
Your place is with me.
-不  我是说  -我知道你想说什么
- No, I meant... - I know what you meant.
你不需要凭借你父亲的名号
You don't need your father's name
或者什么屠龙本领来赢得尊重
or to slay every dragon to be worth something.
你已经做得够多了
You've done enough.
这样足够了
You are enough.
现在你应该寻找自己的幸福
Now you deserve some happiness of your own.
我在你身上找到了幸福
I think I found it in you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
真是个奇迹
What a miracle.
快看
Look!
流星
Shooting star.
又一个
Ooh, another one.
星辰在陨落
The stars are falling.
黑暗说这是它回来的最终预兆
It's the final sign before the Darkness said it would return.
他说它将会横扫这片土地
He said it would sweep the land.
什么东西
What would?
黑死病
The plague.
弗朗西斯  你一晚没睡
Francis, you haven't slept!
贵族和我父亲的大臣
The nobles and my father's advisors
一晚上都在对我进谏
were in my ear all night.
我是法国国王
I am the king of France.
没错  你的确是
Yes, you are.
我从不想事情变成这样
I never wanted it to happen this way.
惧怕自己的父亲
Fearing my own father,
最后变成恨他
hating him at the end.
我看到了淹死在船里的那些尸体
I saw the bodies of those men that drowned in those boats.
那些被屠杀的英雄
Heroes slaughtered.
我看到他那样碰触你的脸
I saw the way that he touched your face.
你当时在赛场上吗
You were at the tournament?
玛丽  虽然你说过我父亲的死
Mary, I know that you said that my father's death
-是上帝的旨意  -弗朗西斯  就是这样的
- was God's will... - Francis, it was.
虽然有人会质问
Although some people would question a God
上帝赋予我们这些权力
who grants us such power,
仅凭我们出身王族
based on nothing but the fortune of our birth.
这不公平  我们被赋予特权
It isn't fair, the privileges we are given.
却也必须为之付出代价
And the price we must pay for them.
我感觉得到自己的改变
I can feel myself changing.
而且并不是变好
And not for the better.
我做的每个决定
Every choice I have made
不论为了保护法国还是苏格兰  甚至是你
to protect France and Scotland, even you,
每次都得经过一番挣扎
for all of them there is a reckoning.
每一次都是真正的我输给了作为女王的我
And it's always the woman who must bow to the queen.
我感觉我杀死了一部分自己
I feel like I'm killing part of myself.
我无视我的内心  直到它可以装聋作哑
But I'm ignoring my heart until it becomes blind and deaf.
我感到自己越来越铁石心肠
I can feel myself growing harder
我担心...
and I worry that I...
我会变成你不爱的样子
that I'm becoming someone you will not love.
那就别改变
Then don't.
不要变得狠心  我会分担你的痛苦
Don't grow harder, share your burdens,
什么事都跟我说  而我...
tell me your darkest truths, and I...
我也坦诚相对
I will tell you mine.
这样一来  我们就不会同床异梦
So we don't end up married but alone,
最终分道扬镳  愈行愈远
two people going down separate paths,
将一切罪恶看成是别无选择
justifying our sins as acts of survival.
如果我们可以相互原谅
If we can forgive each other,
也许就能原谅我们自己
perhaps we can forgive ourselves.
打扰了  女王陛下
Excuse me, Your Grace,
但这是萝拉小姐发来的紧急信件
but there's an urgent letter from Lady Lola.
谢谢你
Thank you.
萝拉要分娩了
Lola's giving birth.
朱利安死了  她现在独自一人
Julien is dead, and she is all alone.
她在哪里
Where is she?
磨坊旁边的房子里
Uh, at-at a house by the mill.
你应该去
You should go.
我去
Me?
就是你
You.
因为你是孩子的父亲
Because you are the father of her child.
因为我想告诉你好久了
Because I've wanted to tell you for months.
因为  萝拉最终也希望你知道
Because, finally, Lola wants you to know it, too.
弗朗西斯  她说她可能活不下来
Francis, she writes that she may not survive.
没有时间了
There is no time to lose.
去陪着她  这是上帝的旨意
Be there when, God willing,
你的孩子要出生了
your child comes into the world.
快点  找到救援后
Hurry, and I will come and join you
我就赶过去
after I have gathered some help.
-一直以来  -我之后会解释
- All this time... - I will explain after.
但现在  我求求你  去陪在她身边
But for now I beg you, be by her side.
快去
Go.
我需要医生
I need a doctor.
或产婆  萝拉需要帮助
Or a midwife. Lola needs help.
没人能够离开或进入城堡
No one will be leaving or entering the castle.
暂时不行  我会和守卫说
Not for some time. I'll speak with the guards.
放下闸门  守住全部大门
The portcullis will be lowered, all gates will be secured.
为什么  发生什么了
Why? What's happening?
附近城镇传来消息
Word has come from surrounding villages.
开始有人死于瘟疫
People are dying of plague.
和染病的人共处一室
Standing in the same room
就有可能被感染
with someone who is ill risks infection.
我知道瘟疫什么样
I know what the plague does.
人们隐瞒他们患病
People are already hiding their sick
生怕自己会被锁在家里
for fear of being locked in their homes with them.
但萝拉  她...
But, Lola, she...
你不能帮她
You cannot help her.
弗朗西斯正要离开城堡
Francis is leaving the castle
去陪着她
to go and be with her!
阻止他
Stop him!
弗朗西斯  等等
Francis, wait!
谢天谢地你还没走
Thank God you haven't left.
怎么了
What is it?
开始有人死去
People are dying.
瘟疫爆发了
The plague has come and it's spreading.
你母亲下令封锁城堡
Your mother has ordered the castle locked down.
萝拉就在不远处
Lola is not far from here.
我会带着她和孩子回来
I shall return with her and the baby.
不  弗朗西斯  你不能走
No, Francis, you can't leave.
你恳求我去陪在她身边
You urged me to be by her side.
你知道她现在不应该孤身奋战
You know she shouldn't be alone now.
这是个坏主意
It's a terrible decision,
但作为统治者
but it's our duty as rulers
我们有责任做出正确决定
to make the right one.
你要去的是乡村  有可能接触到瘟疫
You are going to a village which has likely been exposed to plague.
如果你带回来感染了瘟疫的人...
If you bring back people who may have been infected with it...
人
"People"?
是你的朋友
Your friend.
我的孩子  可能是我唯一的孩子
My child, perhaps my only child.
你不仅是在拿自己的命冒险
You're not just risking your life,
还有城堡里每个人的生命
but everyone in this castle.
如果你走了  带回来感染了瘟疫的人...
If you leave, and you return with anybody who is ill...
玛丽  你说感觉自己变得狠绝了
Mary, you said you felt yourself growing harder.
别变成那样
Don't let it happen.
倾听你的心声
Listen to your heart,
你会听到的  就像我一样
and you will hear it as clearly as I do.
你是法国国王
You are the king of France!
你不再有遵从内心的权利
You no longer have the privilege of obeying your heart!
我不想做那样的国王
That's not the kind of king that I want to be.
把城门关上
Lower the gates.
-但弗朗西斯国王  -他很清楚现状危急
- But King Francis... - Is aware of the threat to us all.
马上关上城门
Lower the gates now.